maxx.co.nz 2012-11-30

# AT Public Transport - Privacy Statement

Auckland Transport (AT) has created this Privacy Statement in relation to the AT Public Transport website [www.AT.co.nz](http://www.at.co.nz/) (formerly the **MAXX Website** ) and the related services offered in conjunction with the AT Public Transport Website ( **Related Services** ) in order to demonstrate its firm commitment to privacy.

This Privacy Statement should be read in conjunction with the General Terms and Conditions of Website Use. By viewing and using the AT Public Transport Website and/or Related Services, you will be deemed to agree to this Privacy Statement. If you do not agree to this Privacy Statement you should stop accessing and using the AT Public Transport Website and Related Services and you should not disclose information to Auckland Transport.

[www.AT.co.nz](http://www.at.co.nz/) is brought to you by Auckland Transport (AT). For more information about Auckland Transport, please visit the [Auckland Transport website](http://www.aucklandtransport.govt.nz/).

Auckland Transport is committed to protecting our customers' personal information. We have created this Privacy Policy to help you understand how we collect, use and protect your personal information when you visit our websites,contact us or use our products and services.

This policy is provided for your information and doesn't limit or exclude your rights under the Privacy Act 1993.

This Privacy Policy covers the following topics:

  1.     What personal information does Auckland Transport collect?
  2.     How does Auckland Transport use your information?
  3.     Sharing your information
  4.     Cookies
  5.     Protecting your information
  6.     Retention and storage
  7.     Accessing your information
  8.     Changes to our Privacy Policy
  9.     Acceptance

###   
1\. What personal information does Auckland Transport collect?

We collect information relating to you that you have provided to us (through registration, completing forms, contacting us, or using our products and services) or that we may have obtained from another source (such as our suppliers, transport operators or from marketing organisations).

This information may include your name, date of birth, address, telephone numbers, information on how you use our products and services (such as your transaction history how much you spend, and browsing activity when visiting one of our websites), lifestyle information and any other information collected in relation to your use of our products and services.

When you visit one of our websites,  Auckland Transport's Internet Service Provider may make a record of your visit and log the following information for statistical purposes:

    Your server address  
    Your top level domain name (for example .com, .gov, .au, .uk etc)  
    The date and time of your visit to the site  
    The pages you accessed and the documents downloaded  
    The previous site you have visited  
    The type of browser you are using

This information about your use is only analysed on a bulk basis for broad demographic content. Individual use is not analysed

If you use one of our websites to complete an online application form, or create an account or register a card, we will only collect the information you provide as part of that process if you complete and submit the application or registration to us.  If you log out of our websites or cancel your application or registration before submitting it, the information you had entered will be automatically deleted.

###   
2\. How does Auckland Transport use your information?

The information that we collect from you may be used by us for a number of purposes connected with our business such as:

2.1 processing your application for registration for use of Auckland Transport services or to access information on our websites made available only to registered users;

2.2 providing you with products and/or services you have requested or administering your account;

2.3 settling accounts with those who provide related services to us;

2.4 dealing with your requests, enquiries or complaints and other customer care related activities;

2.5 carrying out market and product analysis and marketing our products and services generally;

2.6 providing the information to carefully selected third parties (such as our Business Partners) so that they can offer products and services which we reasonably believe may be of interest to you (unless you [](mailto:PrivacyOfficer@aucklandtransport.govt.nz)[ask us](mailto:PrivacyOfficer@aucklandtransport.govt.nz) in writing not to).

2.7 contacting you about our products and services and the products and services of carefully selected third parties which we reasonably believe may be of interest to you (unless you [ask us](mailto:PrivacyOfficer@aucklandtransport.govt.nz) in writing not to). Where such contact is via electronic means, any electronic marketing messages we and/or our selected third parties send will include an unsubscribe facility;

2.8 registering your details and allocating or offering you rewards, discounts or other benefits and fulfilling any requests or requirements you may have in respect of our loyalty or reward programmes and other similar schemes;

2.9 carrying out any activity in connection with a legal, governmental or regulatory requirement on us or in connection with legal proceedings, crime or fraud prevention, detection or prosecution;

2.10 carrying out activities connected with the running of our business such as personnel training, quality control, network monitoring, testing and maintenance of computer and other systems and in connection with the transfer of any part of our business in respect of which you are a customer or a potential customer;

2.11 for general administrative and business purposes.  

###   
3\. Sharing your information

There may be times when we disclose your personal information to third parties. If we do this, we will only disclose your information to:

3.1 those who provide products or services to us, or products or services that support the services that we provide, such as our Business Partners, other suppliers and transport operators;

3.2 anyone who assists us in protecting the operation of the Auckland Transport, and our networks and central solution systems, including the use of monitoring and detection in order to identify potential threats, such as hacking and virus dissemination and other security vulnerabilities;

3.3 anyone who hosts or maintains data centres, service platforms and other infrastructure and systems on behalf of us and our group companies, where your information is processed;

3.4 persons to whom we may be required to pass your information by reason of legal, governmental or regulatory authority including law enforcement agencies and emergency services;

3.5 any person or organisation as authorised by the Privacy Act 1993.

If you have not [opted out](mailto:PrivacyOfficer@aucklandtransport.govt.nz) of receiving marketing material from us or carefully selected third parties who we reasonably believe provide products or services that may be of interest to you, we may also provide your personal information to those third parties.  We will only do this where those third parties have contracted with Auckland Transport to keep the information confidential, or are subject to obligations to protect your personal information.

### 4\. Cookies

"Cookies" are pieces of information that a website transfers to an individual's hard drive for record keeping purposes.  The cookie assigns you an ID which allows Auckland Transport to recognise you when you return to one of our websites.  We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests so users do not have to register each time they use our websites. 

### 5\. Protecting your personal information

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete, up-to-date and stored in a secure environment protected from unauthorised access, use, modification or disclosure.  

### 6\. Retention and storage

We may retain all personal information that we collect (on both our active systems and our archive systems), for as long as is necessary for us to carry out the purposes for which the information was collected (including for the purpose of providing services to you). For registration and account information, this means that the information is likely to be retained for the period of time that we consider your account (registered card or online account) to be "active". An "inactive" card is where the card is not used and no Stored Value or Period Passes are added to the card for a continuous period of 2 years.

The location at which we store your personal information will depend on the nature and purpose of the information and the manner in which you supply it to us. We may use, process, and store your personal information at our premises and/or storage facilities (whether in New Zealand or overseas).

### 7\. Accessing your personal information

You have the right to know whether or not we hold any personal information about you.  You also have the right to access your personal information, if we hold that personal information in a way that it can be readily retrieved. You may request access to the personal information we hold about you by sending an email to PrivacyOfficer@aucklandtransport.govt.nz.

You can ask to see the personal information that we hold about you, or make a request for information under the Local Government and Meetings Act 1987, by sending a written request to:   

Privacy Officer  
Auckland Transport  
Private Bag 2255  
Auckland 1142

You may also [ask us](mailto:PrivacyOfficer@aucklandtransport.govt.nz) to correct, alter or delete any personal information that we hold about you by sending a written request to the above address. It is your responsibility to ensure that personal information provided to us is accurate.  If we do not correct your information in the way you have asked, you can request that we attach to that information a statement of the correction you asked for.

When writing to us, please quote your name and address. We would be grateful if you could also provide brief details of what information you want a copy of (this helps us to more readily locate your data).

In some cases, there may be a charge associated with providing copies of your personal information to you. If so, we will advise you of this prior to sending your information to you. 

### 8\. Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time.    

### 9\. Acceptance

The privacy policy forms a part of our Website Terms and Conditions and should be read in conjunction with them.  By viewing and using our websites or related services offered in conjunction with our websites, you agree to Auckland Transport collecting and using your personal informal information as set out in this Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree to anything in this Privacy Policy (for example if you do not wish to receive marketing material from Auckland Transport or carefully selected third parties), you can either [contact us](mailto:PrivacyOfficer@aucklandtransport.govt.nz) or you can stop accessing or using our websites.

If you decide not to provide personal information requested when you use, register or open an account on one of websites, this may result in services or products (including related services offered in conjunction with our websites) not being offered or provided to you.
